The Register to the Betsy Jolas Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, 1937-2010; Series II
  - Paper, 1
    - Syndicat Professionnel de la Critique Dramatique et Musicale, 1995; 1 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Tagliaferri, Lucia, 1994; 2 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Takashiro, M, 1993; 1 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Takemitsu, Toru, 1973; 1 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Les Talismans
      See Dulong, Aubert
    - Talma, Louise, 1984; 2 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Tamburello, John, 1993; 2 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Tamestit, Antoine, 2007; 1 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Tanaka, Rié, 1996; 1 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Tanglewood Music Center, 1999-2006; 5 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      See also Boston Symphony Orchestra; Gustin, Daniel R.
    - Tantillo, Giovanna, 1994; 2 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Tartakowski, Michel, [1991]; 2 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Tasca, Catherine, 1979-2001; 4 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Taublieb, Diane, 1999; 1 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Tcherepnin, Sue-Ellen (née Hershman), 1998; 1 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Teatro Lirico Sperimentale, 1996-2009; 2 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Telluride Institute, 1989; 1 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Terrisse, Frédéric, 2002; 1 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Tessier, Roger, 1985-1987; 7 (Box 36, Folder 8)
      See also Angers Musiques du XXes
    - Testeniere, Michel, 2002; 4 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Teycheney, Laurent, 1996-2006; 6 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Tezenas, Mme. Léon, No date; 1 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - ?, Th., No date; 1 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Théâtre des Célestins, 1962; 1 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Théâtre des Champs Elysées
      See Durel, Alain
    - Théâtre National de Chaillot, 1984-1987; 4 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Théâtre de la Ville, 1970; 3 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Theodore Presser Company, 1974-1999; 42 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      See also Broido, Arnold; Broido, Thomas; Eastman, Ursula
    - le Thiec, Michel, 1998; 1 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Thomas, Andrew
      See Composers' Forum; Theodore Presser Company
    - Thomas, Augusta Read (Gusty), 1990-1997; 5 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Thomas, John Patrick, 1975-1993, no date; 7 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Thomson, William, 1976-1998; 17 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Thurlow, Jeremy, 1998-2000; 9 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      See also Éditions Salabert; Grove Dictionary of Music
    - Tillard, Francine, 2000; 1 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Timbrell, Charles, 1995; 1 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - ?, Tobé, No date; 2 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Toeplitz, Kasper T., 1989; 3 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Topaz, Muriel (Wife of Jacob Druckman), 1979; 1 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Toral de Adomián, María Teresa, 1982; 1 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Tortelier, (Yan-)Pascal, 1996; 1 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Tournier, Jean-Loup (J.L.), 1976-1997; 13 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Toutain, Sabine, 1989; 2 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Trachier, Olivier, 1994; 2 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Trautmann, Catherine, 1997; 2 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Trawick, Eleanor, 1985; 2 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Treacher, Graham, 1963; 1 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Tremblay, Gilles, 1977-2002; 2 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Trio Arbos, 2005; 1 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      See also Pablo, Luis de
    - Trio á Cordes Circa, No date; 2 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Trio á Cordes Français
      See Caillon, Christiane
    - Trivers, Juliana B., 1997-1998; 2 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      See also Davidovsky, Mario
    - Troncin, Dominique, 1989-1994; 6 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Trouvé, Jacques-Marie, 1986; 1 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Trutat, Alain, 1961-2006; 4 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Trythall, Richard, 2002; 1 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Tual, Denise R., 1978; 1 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Turetzky, Bertram, 1978-1995; 2 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - ?, Ty, 1994; 2 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - Una Corda Editions Musicales, 1996; 1 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - United Music Publishers LTD (UMP), 1982-1996; 35 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      See also Alphonse Leduc Éditeurs de Musique; Leduc, Jean
    - Universal Edition A.G., 1963-1972; 6 (Box 36A, Folder 1)
    - Université de Lille III, 1987; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 1)
    - Université de Paris I - Panthéon-Sorbonne, 1984-1985; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 1)
      See also Bosseur, Dominique; Guiomar, Michel
    - Université de Paris IV - Sorbonne, 1986-1995; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 1)
      See also Gut, Serge
    - Université de Paris VIII - Vincennes
      See Andreani, Eveline
    - Université de Paris X - Nanterre
      See Castarede, Marie-France
    - University at Buffalo, SUNY, 1976-1988; 8 (Box 36A, Folder 1)
    - University of California - Los Angeles (UCLA), 1991; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 1)
    - University of California Press, 1981-1983; 12 (Box 36A, Folder 1)
      See also Moe, Lawrence
    - University of California - San Diego (UCSD), 1978-1992; 14 (Box 36A, Folder 1)
      See also Plantamura, Carol; Reynolds, Roger
    - University of Chicago
      See Retzel, Frank
    - University of Colorado, 1989; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 2)
    - University of Huddersfield
      See Steinitz, Richard
    - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 1992-1993; 10 (Box 36A, Folder 2)
    - University of Michigan School of Music, 2005-2006; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 2)
    - University of Minnesota
      See Paulu, Burton
    - University of Ottawa
      See Gellman, Steven
    - University of Southern California (USC), 1993; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 2)
      See also Stein, Leonard; Thomson, William
    - The University of Tasmania, 1984; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 2)
    - University of Texas at Austin
      See Staley, Thomas F.
    - University of Victoria, 1987; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 2)
    - Uriesen, Samuel, 1993; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 2)
    - Urwin, Ray W., 1978; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 2)
    - Valantin, Simone, 2000; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 3)
    - Valéry, François, 1985-1988; 4 (Box 36A, Folder 3)
    - Valette, Marthe, 1994; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 3)
    - Valorz, Lolita and Paolo, 1994; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 3)
    - Van Oosten, Roel, 1984-1992; 13 (Box 36A, Folder 3)
    - Vanek, Mojmir, 1981; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 3)
    - Varholy, Daniel Joseph, 1984; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 3)
    - Vatelot, Étienne, 1979; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 3)
    - Veber, Dr. Zdenka, 1986; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 3)
    - Verband deutscher Komponisten und Musikwissenschaftler (VDK), 1965; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 3)
    - Verdehr, Elsa (née Ludewig), 1998-1999; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Verdehr, Walter, 1996-2001; 5 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Vermaelen, Denis, 1992-1993; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Vermont Symphony Orchestra, 1981; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Vernède, Arielle, 1991; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Vetera et Nova
      See Comoy, Colette
    - Vezin, Sylvette, 1992; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Vilcosqui, Marcel, 1977; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - de Villers, André, 1995; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Villeneuve, Paquerette, 2002; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Villeurbanne Information Femmes Familles (VIFF), 1985; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Viola-Forschungsgesellshaft, 1969; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Vitez, Antoine, 1975-1992; 10 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Vivien, Guy, 1986; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Voutsinas, Gerassimos, 1989; 4 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
    - Vozlinksy, Pierre, 1974-1978; 5 (Box 36A, Folder 4)
      See also Radiodiffusion-Télévision Française; Radio France
    - Wadsworth, Charles, 1974-1976; 7 (Box 36A, Folder 5)
      See also Chamber Music Society of Lincoln Center
    - Wagner, Christian, 1982; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 5)
    - Wagner, Laurent, No date; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 5)
    - Wahl, Bernard, No date; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 5)
    - Wajyma, Hiroko, 1988-1989; 5 (Box 36A, Folder 5)
    - Walsh, Diane, 1987-1989; 12 (Box 36A, Folder 5)
    - Walsh-Wilson, Rita, 1989; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 5)
    - Wang, Chin-Hwa, 1979; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 5)
    - Ward, Jennifer, 2002; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 5)
    - Washington Post
      See Page, Tim
    - Webb, Barrie, 1996; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Weber, Alain, 1982-1991; 4 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Webster, Albert K.
      See New York Philharmonic
    - Wehage, Paul, 1982; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Wehrlin, François, 2004; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Weinrich, Carl, 1978; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Weinstein, Micheline, 1969-1993; 4 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Weiss, Norbert, 1990; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Wellesley College, 1974; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Werner, Maurice, 1967-1974; 8 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
      See also Festival International d'Art Contemporain de Royan; Festival de Shiraz Persepolis
    - West, Ann M., 1994; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Wetherill, Linda, 1981-1984; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - White, Barbara, 1987-1991; 4 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Whiteley, Sally W., 1989; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Whitney, Robert
      See The Louisville Orchestra
    - Whitten, Brian, 1995; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Wicks, Christopher, 1994; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Wieder-Atherton, Sonia, 1980-1993, no date; 10 (Box 36A, Folder 6)
    - Williams, Jan, 1982-1989; 8 (Box 36A, Folder 7)
    - Wils, Valérie, 1999; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 7)
    - Wilson-Johnson, David, No date; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 7)
    - Wislin, Stéphane, 1969; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 7)
    - Wodehouse, Artis, 1983-1984; 6 (Box 36A, Folder 7)
    - Won, Yong Sook, 1978-1999; 7 (Box 36A, Folder 7)
      See also Feldman, Morton
    - Worms, Michèle, 1991-1992; 4 (Box 36A, Folder 7)
    - Wou-ki, Zao, 1993; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 7)
    - Wyner, Yehudi, 1979-2010; 18 (Box 36A, Folder 7)
    - Xenakis, Françoise (Wife of Iannis), 2000; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 8)
    - Xenakis, Iannis, 1978; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 8)
    - Xu, Yi, 1995-2006; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 8)
    - Xuereb, Pierre-Henri, 1992-1993; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 8)
    - Yale University, 1992-1996; 11 (Box 36A, Folder 8)
      See also Bresnick, Martin; Giroud, Vincent; Laderman, Ezra; Nelson, Philip F.; Norfolk Chamber Music Festival; Perlis, Vivian; Shailor, Barbara A.; Soullière, Anne-Marie
    - Yale University Press, 1994; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 8)
    - Yannotta, Bernard, No date; 1 (Box 36A, Folder 8)
    - YWCA of Washington, D.C., 1974; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 8)
    - Zaffini, Clément, 1975; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 9)
    - Zarankin, Julia, 2002; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 9)
    - Zedda, Paolo
      See Association Française des Professeurs de Chant
    - Zehrfuss, Bernard
      See Académie des Beaux-Arts
    - Zivy, Pierre, 1994-1996; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 9)
    - Zollman, Ronald, No date; 2 (Box 36A, Folder 9)
    - Zourabichvili, Nicolas, 2006; 6 (Box 36A, Folder 9)
    - Zumbach, André
      See Radio Suisse Romande
    - Zygel, Jean François, 1990-1992; 3 (Box 36A, Folder 9)
    - Unidentified - From Betsy Jolas, 1967-1995; 37 (Box 36A, Folder 10)
    - Unidentified - To Betsy Jolas, 1950-2002, no date; 56 (Box 36A, Folder 11)
  - Electronic, 2
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    The USB drive this content was received on has been imaged and transfered to the server noted in the Processing Information note. The individual files have been exported from this disc image for ease of access. File formats include: .eml, .doc, .txt, .odt, .rtf, .pdf, and .html.
    - Albèra, Philippe, 2007; 1
    - Alex and Shery, 2009; 1
    - Alphonse Leduc Éditeurs de Musique, 2003-2010; 4
    - Amy, Gilbert, 2007-2010; 7
    - Anderson, Julian, 2006-2009; 4
    - Angster, Armand, 2008-2010; 8
    - Apicella, Anne, 2008; 1
    - Argatti, 2007; 3
    - Bacon, Alexis, 2004; 1
    - Baguet, Jacques, 2010; 1
    - Barlerin, Edouard, 2007; 1
    - Bayen, Bruno, 2008; 1
    - Bedrossian, Franck, 2010; 1
    - Benjamin, George, 2006; 1
    - Bell, Millicent, 2009-2010; 3
    - Bello, Aurelien, 2007; 1
    - Bill, 2009; 1
    - Blank, William, 2007-2010; 8
    - Blondeau, Thierry, 2007-2008; 2
    - Bon, André, 2007; 2
    - Boepple, [Hans?], 2004; 1
    - Boosey Hawkes, 2009; 1
    - Borsarello, Jacques, 2007; 1
    - Bortoli, Stephane, 2009; 1
    - Bugallo, Helena, 2008; 1
    - Cadoret, Marie-Violaine, 2009; 1
    - Camus, Renaud, 2009; 1
    - Caws, Mary Ann, 2002; 1
    - Comité Reverdu, 2009; 1
    - Chris, 2006; 1
    - Conde, Gérard, 2006; 1
    - Costes, Françoise, 2009; 1
    - Crumb, George, 2006; 1
    - Daugherty, Michael, 2009-2010; 4
    - Deissler, Dirk, 2002; 1
    - Desurmont, Marguerite, 2007-2010; 4
    - Djupstrom, Michael, 2009-2010; 1
    - Dominique, 2006; 1
    - Dubois, Paul-Alexandre, 2008-2009; 2
    - Dubost, André, 2010; 1
    - Edwards, Michael, 2009; 1
    - Eötvos, Maria, 2004; 1
    - Espinasse, François, 2007; 1
    - Feder, Guy, 2009; 1
    - Galerie Lezarts, 2009; 1
    - Gangneron, Christian, 2007; 2
    - Gaussin, Allain, 2006; 1
    - Gottlieb, Jay, 2007-2008; 6
    - Harleman, Ann, 2007; 3
    - Harnik, Elisabeth, 2010; 1
    - Heugel-Petit, Catherine, 2007; 1
    - Hlawsa, Malgorzata (Gosia), 2007-2010; 8
    - Iles, Marton, 2009; 1
    - Hyla, Lee, 2010; 1
    - Illouz, Antoine, 2010; 1
    - Illouz, Claire, 2007-2010; 9
    - Illouz, Michael, 2007-2009; 2
    - Jolas, Mia, 2009; 3
    - Kashkashian, Kim, 2007; 1
    - Kleinzahler, August, 2009; 1
    - Kolb, Barbara, 2009; 1
    - Kraft, Nathalie, 2006; 1
    - La Grange, Henry-Louis de, 2006-2009; 2
    - Le Bouffo, Emilie, 2009; 1
    - Lettre du Musicien, 2004-2009; 2
    - Levinas, Michael, 2009; 2
    - Levinson, Gerald (Jerry), 2008; 1
    - Levy, Ernst, 2010; 1
    - Mansanti, Céline, 2007; 4
    - Mantovani, Bruno, 2007; 2
    - Martin, Nathalie, 2009; 1
    - Memed, Orhan, 2007-2010; 17
    - Merlet, Dominique, 2008; 1
    - Milhaud, Daniel, 2009; 1
    - Molina, Christopher, 2004; 1
    - Monde Carnet, Le, 2003; 1
    - Monier-Illouz, Esther, 2007-2010; 20
    - Monnet, Marc, 2005-2009; 4
    - Muraro, Roger, 2007-2009; 3
    - Musée d'Art Moderne Grand Duc Jean, 2005; 1
    - Myers, 2009; 1
    - Narboni, François, 2004-2005; 2
    - Navarro, Catherine, 2007; 1
    - Opéra International, 2003; 1
    - O'Leary, Sheila, 2009; 1
    - Ortega, Jéremy Douville, 2010; 3
    - Overbeck, Lois, 2004-2010; 2
    - Pascal, Robert, 2005; 1
    - Perlis, Vivian, 2007-2010; 21
    - Pesson, Gérard, 2007-2009; 7
    - Petit, Arnaud, 2009; 1
    - Pillsbury, Barbara, 2004-2007; 3
    - Pillsbury, Henry, 2009; 1
    - Plantamura, Carol, 2007-2009; 3
    - Pochon, Virginie, 2009; 1
    - Queré, Yves, 2008-2009; 2
    - Rands, Bernard, 2010; 1
    - Range, Ulrike, 2004-2009; 2
    - Ravenne, Catherine, 2008; 1
    - Reimann, Aribert, 2009-2010; 3
    - Rockwell, Svetlana, 2009-2010; 5
    - Rindfleisch, Andrew, 2008; 1
    - Roussel, Léonard, 2007; 1
    - Rumold, Rainer, 2004-2010; 13
    - Sally and Jim, 2004; 1
    - Samuel, Virgina, 2009; 1
    - Schmitz, Johannes, 2010; 1
    - Shloss, Carol, 2002; 1
    - Soper, Libby, 2008-2010; 2
    - Soullière, Anne-Marie, 2007-2010; 3
    - Soullière, Kathleen, 2007; 1
    - Sowerwine, Charles "Chips", 2008; 3
    - Sutter, Sandrine, 2007; 1
    - Taberlet, Anne-Christine, 2007; 1
    - Tamestit, Antoine, 2007-2009; 3
    - Theodore Presser Company, 2008; 1
    - Trapani, Christopher, 2010; 1
    - Tremblay, Gilles, 2009; 1
    - Thurlow, Jeremy, 2008; 2
    - Tucker, Colin, 2007; 2
    - Van Daele, Christine, 2007-2009; 3
    - Weeger, Yves, 2009; 1
    - Williams, Amy, 2008; 2
    - Wolman, Amnon, 2008-2009; 2
    - Woolrich, John, 2009; 2
- Teaching materials, 1960-2006; Series III
  This series is divided into two subseries: Lecture Notes and Analytical Notes. Organized chronologically, the lecture notes are listed with their title and a location. Jolas's lectures address French music, 20th century composers, and various other musical subjects.
  The analytical notes, or "notes d'analyse," are arranged alphabetically by composer. The notes feature composers such as J.S. Bach, Beethoven, Brahms, Stravinsky, Schoenberg and Xenakis.
  - Lecture notes, 1
    - Darmstadt, 1960 (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - French culture, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - [On French composers], St. John's College, 1969 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Bali, 1972-1973 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Tanglewood, 1973,1976 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - "New Music from Paris," Princeton University, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Twentieth-century American composers, 1976 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Mills College, I, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Mills College, II, 1979 (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Musique Francaise, 1985-1986 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987-2006 (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Colloque "A voix haute", 1992 (Box 37, Folder 12)
    - "Penser Quatuor," Fifth string quartet, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 13)
    - "Frauenleben," Harvard University, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 14)
    - "Musique et narrative", 1995-2002 (Box 37, Folder 15)
    - Festival de Charonne, 1995-1998 (Box 37, Folder 16)
    - "Milhaud, Messiaen et l'enseignement de la composition," Bicentennial of Paris Conservatoire, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 17)
    - "Pierrot Lunaire-Episode Second 'ohne worte'", 1997 (Box 37, Folder 18)
    - Tenth Anniversary Festival de Charonne, 1997 (Box 37, Folder 19)
    - American Academy in Rome, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 20)
    - Lassus, 1999 (Box 37, Folder 21)
    - American Academy in Berlin, 2000-2001 (Box 37, Folder 22)
    - Debussy Festival, Bard College, 2001 (Box 37, Folder 23)
    - Three lectures, Centre Acanthes, 2002 (Box 37, Folder 24)
    - "French Composers Today," University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, 2003 (Box 37, Folder 25)
    - [Music in France after Debussy] Tokyo, 2006 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Analytical notes, 2
    - Bach, J.S. (Box 38, Folder 1)
      Magnificat; Messe en si
    - [Bagpipes] (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Bartok, Bela (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Beethoven, Ludwig (Box 38, Folder 4)
      Grosse Fugue opus 133; opus 59; opus 127; opus 130; opus 132
    - Beethoven, Ludwig (Box 38, Folder 5)
      9th symphony; opus 106; Fugue; Missa Solemnis; Scherzo opus 31 number 2
    - Berg, Alban (Box 38, Folder 6)
      Lyric Suite; Wozzeck
    - Berio, Luciano (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Berlioz, Hector (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Boulez, Pierre (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Boulez, Pierre (Box 38, Folder 10)
      1st Sonate
    - Brahms, Johannes (Box 38, Folder 11)
      opus 109 Symphony number 9; Lied
    - Brown, Earle (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Carter, Elliott (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Chopin, Frederic (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - [Composition Exercises] (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - [Concertos] (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Debussy, Claude (Box 38, Folder 17)
      Pelleas et Melisande
    - Debussy, Claude (Box 38, Folder 18)
      Jeux; other works
    - Debussy, Claude (Box 38, Folder 19)
      La Mer
    - Debussy, Claude (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Debussy, Claude (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - de Pablo, Luis (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - Des Pres, J.; Dutilleux; Fauré (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - Donatoni, Franco (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - Dufay, Guillaume (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - Genise de Formes; Gesualdo; Ives (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Haydn, Joseph, Die Schopfung (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Kagel; Lassus; Ligeti; Lutoslawsky (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Mahler; Messiaen (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Mixed (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Mixed (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Mixed (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Mixed (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Monteverdi (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Mozart; Ockaghem (Box 39, Folder 9)
      Opera
    - Polyphonic notation (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Purcell, Henry (Box 39, Folder 11)
      Quartets
    - Ravel, Maurice (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Schnebel, Dieter (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Schubert, Franz (Box 40, Folder 3)
      Lieder; Fantasie in C major
    - Schumann, Robert (Box 40, Folder 4)
      Kreisleriana
    - Schoenberg, Arnold (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Schutz; Stockhausen (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Strauss, Richard (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Stravinsky, Igor, Les Noces (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Stravinsky, Igor, Petrouchka (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Stravinsky, Igor (Box 66, Folder 7)
      Rite of Spring
    - Stravinsky, Igor (Box 66, Folder 8)
      Various
    - Varese, Edgar (Box 40, Folder 8)
      Variations
    - Variations (Mixed), 1986 (Box 40, Folder 9)
      Composers Included: Bach, Beethoven, Brahms, Byrd, Couperin, Handel, Haydn, Purcell
    - Webern, Anton, Quatour, Op. 28; Trio, Op. 20; Op. 3-4; Op. 6; 5 pieces, Op. 10; Symphony, Op. 21; Variations, Op. 27 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Xenakis, Iannis (Box 40, Folder 11)
      20th century general
- Writings, 1940-2009; Series IV
  This series is divided into two subseries: Writings by Jolas and Writings by Others. The first subseries includes writings and written drafts of presentations by Betsy Jolas. The second subseries includes both published works and original manuscripts--most notably, a "lesson in poetics" given to Jolas by James Joyce.
  - Writings by Jolas, 1
    - Marsyas literary magazine (5 issues), 1944-1945 (Box 41b)
    - Heugel notes for music publications, 1963-1967 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Translation of "Sur la grande fugue" by Joseph Kerman, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - "Voix et musique", 1972 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - "Des deux cotes de l'Atlantique", 1986 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Molto Espressivo, 1997 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      draft chapters, notes
    - "Apres..." Colloque Roger Désormière, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Molto Espressivo, 1998 (Box 41, Folder 7)
      corrections, draft chapters, notes
    - Molto Espressivo, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Happy Birthday" Les Arts Florissants 20th Anniversary, 1999 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - "Laurent Martin, portrait d'un eleve et d'un ami", 1999 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - "A propos de Wanderlied", 2003-2004 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - "Pretentaine", 2004 (Box 41, Folder 12)
      draft
    - Pierre Boulez Documentary, BBC Radio, 2005 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - "Many happy returns...", 2005 (Box 41, Folder 14)
      [on Pierre Boulez at 80]
    - "Domaine Prive Betsy Jolas", 2006 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - "Edith Canat de Chizy!" (Box 41, Folder 16)
      no date
    - "Gilbert Amy" (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 18)
      corrections to "La musique sous les mots dans les operas de Betsy Jolas"
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1968-2009, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Writings by others, 2
    - "Dans La Chaleur Vacante" by Andre Du Bouchet, 1961; 1995; Two editions, published by Mercvre de France. (Box 41, Folder 20)
      Both include dedications by the author.
    - "At the hour of night" by Thomas Moore. Copied by James Joyce, for Betsy Jolas, 1940 (Box 41a, Folder 1)
      "Scansion. A lesson in 'poetics' given to Betsy Jolas (aged 14) by James Joyce, when both were refugees from the war, during the summer of 1940, in St. Gerand-le-Puy, Allier."
    - "L'Oeil" par Victor Hugo; "Les Soldats" de Reinhold Lenz; "Revolving Door" by Frank Moore, 1945-1968 (Box 41a, Folder 2)
      "L'Oeil", published copy with annotations, dedication by Andre du Bouchet; "Les Soldats" screenplay (typescript), "projet non realise"; "Revolving Door" poem, holograph ink.
    - Notes (Box 41a, Folder 3)
      Notes on literature; notes from John Cage lecture
- Programs, 1943-2010; Series V
  This series consists chiefly of programs for concerts in which Betsy Jolas performed or had works performed. Other items include conference/festival programs, brochures, programs for awards ceremonies, articles and newspaper reviews.
  Organized by date, materials span Jolas's career from her earliest church, choir, and dance recitals through her 80th birthday celebration concerts and beyond. Events of note include performances at or by: Carnegie Hall/Lincoln Center, Tanglewood Festival, Chamber Music Society, Opera de Bastille, Opera de Paris, BBC Symphony Orchestra, Concord String Quartet, Stockholm Philharmonic Orchestra, and Groupe Vocal de France. Ceremonial programs include the Prix Italia 1961, Cannes Film Festival 1980, and various honorary concerts.
  - 1943-1946 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - 1947-1954 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - 1955-1962 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - 1964-1966 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - 1967 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - 1968 (Box 42, Folder 6)